{
    "id": "654a07edbec14a9fbd903940457581f7",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. the minister tomorrow.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to refer to future events that are already arranged.",
            "answers": [
                "see",
                "am seeing",
                "would see"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0a335d18e5d744c2a52f877e7fd3c340"
        },
        {
            "question": "‘The phone is ringing.’ ‘I ………………………. it.’",
            "description": "Will is used to announce our decisions.",
            "answers": [
                "will answer",
                "would answer",
                "am answering"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b57a0cb8eee24dbcb9ab5647a1f30e5f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Good luck with the exam. I ………………………… of you.",
            "description": "The future continuous is used to say that something will be in progress at a particular moment in the future.",
            "answers": [
                "am thinking",
                "will have thought",
                "will be thinking"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "51672f8728bd41e0b414b276c0a77561"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. I turn the heating on?",
            "description": "We use shall in polite offers and requests.",
            "answers": [
                "Will",
                "Would",
                "Shall"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "8720ccc18cd6493bbf793179a47b0e91"
        },
        {
            "question": "All the trouble ………………………… by you.",
            "description": "We use the passive verb here because the subject is not the doer of the action.",
            "answers": [
                "caused",
                "was caused",
                "have caused"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7f2c2f9704564cb4bed12b9792f50a33"
        },
        {
            "question": "When you phoned I ……………………….. in the garden.",
            "description": "When we talk about two past events, we often use the past continuous for the longer background action.",
            "answers": [
                "have been working",
                "had been working",
                "was working"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d9ac3522ea24417aa65852e040f4fb0a"
        },
        {
            "question": "After I ………………………… with him for a few weeks, I developed a strange liking for him.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used for the earlier of two past actions.",
            "answers": [
                "have worked",
                "had worked",
                "working"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b69faa74585b4ba3a0b41d77202bd9ca"
        },
        {
            "question": "When we were children we ……………………. go swimming every Sunday.",
            "description": "Both would and used to can refer to repeated actions in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "used to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "300ef1a543904134b66bec7faa2485d7"
        },
        {
            "question": "It would have been nice if he ………………………. us.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "thanks",
                "thanked",
                "had thanked"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "fb600a95c4644034b9b778920a4c6610"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sulphuric acid ……………………….. most metals.",
            "description": "We use the simple future to talk about habits and characteristic behavior.",
            "answers": [
                "would dissolve",
                "will dissolve",
                "dissolved"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8efe61a5aec44185a4bff4b1c2cbf938"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… the whole job by this evening.",
            "description": "We use the future perfect tense to indicate that an action or situation will have been completed by a certain point of time in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "will be finishing",
                "will have finished",
                "had finished"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "46c87cf3d7cc4ce88c4cc84433852b8e"
        }
    ]
}